KOTOMI ANN NOGUCHI

Lawrenceville, GA 30044 • <u>kotomi.noguchi@gmail.com</u> • (404) 649-1920

GitHub | LinkedIn | Blog | Portfolio

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full-stack developer with a background in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming with RESTful API Architecture. Previous experience as a project manager using Agile methodologies in both web development and e-commerce. Adept at working in cross-cultural environments from teaching at public schools in Kyoto and living in Japan, South Korea, and Denmark.

TECHNICAL & PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

JavaScript (ES6), React, Redux, AJAX, Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, Node, Express, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Postgres, SQL, Heroku, Git, MVC, Jira, Agile Methodologies, Figma, MaterializeCSS, Material UI, Advanced Japanese

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Vacay Away, GitHub | Demo

Vacation planner designed for flexible scheduling, with the ability to set activities to specific vacation days or to the wishlist.

- Built a dynamic and seamless UI with horizontal scrolling components using React.js and Material UI
- Applied Redux and Redux-Thunk to provide accessibility to data in a single global store which allows asynchronous dispatching and creates a code structure that's easier to test, maintain, and scale

Flappy Bernie, GitHub | Demo

Interactive spin-off game of Flappy Bird, where the objective is to navigate through the pipes.

- Constructed engaging gameplay UI using Object Oriented Javascript, HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap
- Improved user experience by leveraging AJAX calls for data interactions between the client and Rails API, fetching the top scores from the database asynchronously

Life is Brewtiful, GitHub | Demo

Brewery reviewing app for beer lovers all over the U.S. with search tools to effortlessly filter through breweries.

- Designed Rails application with features like the "Top 100" page and user profile pictures using the Active Storage gem to boost engagement and build community
- Utilized Open Brewery DB's API to pull and store 8,000+ brewery data objects in PostgreSQL database
- Expanded user login options by including authentication with FaceBook and Google accounts via OmniAuth

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Visiture, LLC Atlanta, GA

Technical Account Manager

May 2019 – September 2020

- Managed 2-4 development projects at a time, writing concise, actionable tasks using the Agile methodology for the web developers to meet project deadlines and maintain client budget
- Optimized client e-commerce processes through native and custom Magento software, resulting in increased website traffic by up to 75% and sales conversion by 20%

The Japan Exchange and Teaching Program

Emory University, Goizueta Business School

Kyoto City, Japan

Assistant Language Teacher

July 2016 – July 2018

- Collaborated with over 30 public educators within teams across five schools to develop and improve lesson plans
- Volunteered to lead high school student groups for overnight weekend English camps to immerse them in English-speaking environments before leaving for their homestay programs in Australia

ExpandLab, LLC Atlanta, GA

Data Configuration Analyst Intern

October 2015 -July 2016

- Migrated clients' e-commerce sites to the Magento platform, performing online store, catalog, shipping, payment, cache, and SEO configurations to increase online sales and reach
- Screened quality control prior to project releases to ensure optimal user experience on client websites

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Atlanta, GA

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and Java Script Program

Atlanta, GA

Bachelor of Business Administration, Concentration: Strategic Management Consulting

May 2016

April 2021

Cumulative GPA: **3.70/4.0**